NEIL CASAANDRA

more than 8 years of QA Engineer experience in ensuring the quality and reliability of software products and services. I have expertise in test planning, manual testing, automated testing, API testing, and database testing and others. Currently pursuing Master Degree in IT - Data Analytics, to boarden my horizon in the industry.

Contacts	Skills
0466534573	Test Planning, Execution, and Report
neilsudharmono@gmail.com	Test Case / Scenarios management (Testrail, XRAY, Spreadsheet)
Newcastle, NSW	Manual & Exploratory Testing
in https://www.linkedin.com/in/	API Testing (Postman, Swagger)
neil-casaandra-b72308a7/	CMS Testing (Kentico, Optimizely, Kontent, Sitecore, Umbraco)
https://github.com/neilsudharmon	Basic Programming & Automated Testing (Cypress, Java,
Certifications	Javascript)
ISTQB Foundation Level	Load Testing (JMeter, K6, Flood)
ISTQB Performance Tester	Compatibility Testing (Browserstack, DevTools, Actual Devices)
IELTS 7.5	Database Testing (SQL, MongoDB, Firebase, MySQL)
PTE 77	Accessibility testing (Wave, Lighthouse, Chrome DevTools)
	Agile Team Management (JIRA, Confluence, Tempo, etc.)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sudo Roux, Sydney Jan 2023 - Present

Senior QA Engineer - Remote Full Time to Freelance

- · Create QA standards within the company,
- Test plans creation, developing scenarios, conducting manual, exploratory and CMS testing,
- · Ensuring the products' compatibility,
- Documenting Test Report, Release Note, and as-built details for each project.
- Load testing

Notable Projects: Sydney Royal Easter Show, Royal Agriculture Society of NSW, Sydney Showground, College of Law, Mother Hubbard

Senior Automation QA Engineer - Remote Full Time

interviewing junior QA before they join the team.

 Product testing, conducted Test planning, test scenario development, using Cypress.io and Codecept.js for automated testing, manual testing, API testing with Postman, and checking databases with Postgresql, help in

Xendit, Singapore Nov 2022 - Jan 2023

Brankas, Singapore April 2022 - Nov 2022

Senior QA Engineer - Remote Full Time

 Product Testing, conducted test planning, scenario development, reporting, utilizing Cypress.io for automated testing, manual testing, API testing with Postman, and database checking with Postgresql for Fintech product, mentor and trained junior QA team members

Luminary, Melbourne Oct 2019 - April 2022

QA Analyst - Remote Full Time

- I've worked across diverse industries including Super, Charity, Electrical, and E-commerce for Australian companies,
- Conducted test planning, scenario development, reporting, manual testing, automated testing with Cypress.io, API testing using Postman, and performance testing with tools like K6 and Flood.io.
- CMS testing on platforms such as Kentico Xperience, Umbraco, Sitecore, Kontent, and Optimizely,
- Conducted accessibility testing using WAVE, Compatibility testing via Browserstack
- Client walkthroughs and mentoring junior QA team members.

Notable Projects: Clipspec by Clipsal, Fred Hollows, Cancer Council, EISS Super, LUCRF Super, Healthy Life & Pet Culture by Woolworths

The Development Studio, Bali April 2019 - Oct 2019

Test Analyst - Full Time

 Did Test planning, scenario development, and reporting for e-learning web application products, manual and automated testing using Cypress.io for automated testing and Postman for API testing. I used Testrail, Confluence, and JIRA for testing management, performance testing using JMeter

Notable Projects: E2Language and E2School

DGIT, Melbourne Nov 2017 - Mar 2019

Quality Analyst - Full Time

- Collaborating with a distributed team across New Zealand, Australia, South Africa, and the UAE for implementation of Telflow product.
- Conducted test planning, scenario creation, and reporting utilizing Testrail
 and JIRA. My proficiency extends to automated testing using Selenium with
 Cucumber, API testing with SoapUI, and performance testing employing
 JMeter and Grafana.
- Database testing, specifically with MongoDB. Implementing continuous integration with DevOps, particularly leveraging Jenkins, I contribute to seamless testing of Elastic Search.

OCBC NISP Bank, Bandung July 2014 - Oct 2017

Quality Analyst - Full Time

- Responsible for manual testing on desktop, web application and AS400 systems for banking with, test planning, test scenario development beforehand. In addition, i also debugged issue with Visual Studio and SQL Profiler, as well as database testing with SQL Server.
- Moreover, i led manual deployment in UAT and production environments, I
 ensure seamless transitions. As a source code gatekeeper using Visual
 Sourcesafe, my expertise contributes to robust core bank testing,
 particularly with AS400 systems.

EDUCATION

King's Own Institute 2023 - present

Master of Information Technology - Data Analytics

Newcastle, NSW, Australia

Maranatha Christian University 2010 - 2014

Bachelor of Information Technology

Bandung, Indonesia - GPA 3.56 / 4.00

REFERENCES

Luminary

Matthew Stobo, QA Manager and Senior Front End Developer

mjstobo@gmail.com 0403275041

Sudo Roux

Dillon Hicks, CEO

<u>dillon.hicks@sudoroux.com.au</u> 1300753499